Now, we've seen the importance of using
现在我们已经认识到
both low pass and high pass filters for accurate edge detection.
要有准确的边缘检测效果 结合使用低通和高通过滤器有多重要
But even with these used together,
但就算两者结合使用
edge detection is still a very complex problem.
边缘检测也仍是个很棘手的难题
We have to think about what level of intensity change constitutes an edge,
我们需要思考 什么样的强度变化会形成边缘
and how we can consistently detect and represent both thin and thick edges.
如果边缘薄厚程度不同 我们又要怎么检测并将其表示出来呢？
One of the best and most frequently used edge detectors that
最好用也是最常用的边缘检测器之一
takes all of these questions into account is the canny edge detector.
叫做 canny 边缘检测器 它能解决上述两个问题
Canny edge detection is used very widely in computer vision applications because it
canny 边缘检测器在计算机视觉领域应用十分广泛
goes through a series of steps that consistently produce accurately detected edges.
因为该检测器会借助一系列操作 不断生成精准的检测边缘
First, it filters out noise using a Gaussian blur.
首先 检测器用高斯模糊过滤掉噪声
Second, it finds the strength and direction of edges in an image using Sobel filters,
然后用 Sobel 过滤器确定图像边缘的强度和方向
and we've gone through steps like these before.
我们之前也进行过类似的操作
Third, using the output of the Sobel filters,
接着 借助 Sobel 过滤器的输出
Canny then applies non-maximum suppression which
Canny 会用非极大抑制
looks at the strength and direction of each detected edge and selects
来观察每个检测边缘的强度和方向
the local maximum pixel to create
选出局部最大像素
consistent one pixel wide thin lines that align with the strongest edges.
从而把最强的边缘绘制成连续的、一个像素宽的细线
Finally, it uses a process called hysteresis thresholding to isolate the best edges.
最后 用滞后阀值来分离最佳边缘
Hysteresis is a double thresholding process.
滞后阀值是双阀值化操作
Let's see an example taking a one pixel wide cross-section of an image.
以某图一像素宽的横切面为例
Here the curve represents the level of intensity
这里的曲线代表边缘强度
in edges where the peaks are very strong edges.
峰值指的是十分强的边缘
To perform hysteresis, we define
使用滞后阀值时 我们要确定
a high threshold that allows these strong edges to pass through.
一个高阀值 以便允许这些强边缘通过
And we use a second low threshold too.
再设置一个低阀值
Any edge below this low threshold is considered weak and discarded.
任何低于该阀值的边缘即为弱边缘 会被舍弃
But an edge whose strength falls in between this low threshold and
但位于高低阀值之间的边缘
the high threshold will be kept only when it's connected to another strong edge.
只有当其与另一个强边缘相连时 才会得到保留
This way Canny eliminates weak edges and noise and isolates the edges
这样一来 Canny 就删除了弱边缘 消除了噪声
that are the most connected and therefore are most
还将关联最强的那些边缘分离了出来
likely to be part of an object boundary.
而这些边缘恰恰最可能是物体边界的一部分
And because Canny emphasizes important edges,
由于 Canny 着重强调重要边缘
we'll see that it's very useful in boundary and shape detection.
所以它特别适合检测边界和形状
The code to implement Canny edge detection is fairly simple.
实现 Canny 边缘检测的代码十分简单
Here, I've read in an image of a sunflower as an example.
以这张向日葵照片为例 我将其读取出来
I'll first convert it to grayscale using CVT color.
用 cvtColor 将图片转为灰度图像
Then I'll begin to implement Canny edge detection.
然后开始实现 Canny 边缘检测
I'll have to define lower and upper thresholds for implementing hysteresis.
要实现滞后阀值 我要定义上下限
The edges that are detected range in intensity values from 0 to 255.
边缘检测的强度范围在 0 到 255 之间
So I'll set the low threshold to 120 and the upper threshold to twice that value, 240.
所以我将下限定为 120 上限定为下限的两倍 即 240
It's recommended to use a low to high threshold ratio between 1:2 like this,
建议将高低阀值的比例保持在 1:2 就像这样
or 1:3 for best results.
或者 1:3 这两个比例的效果最佳
Then we can use OpenCVs Canny function.
然后使用 OpenCV 的 Canny 函数
This takes in our grayscale image and
该函数需要输入的参数有 灰度图像以及
our lower and upper thresholds that we just defined.
刚才定义的阀值上下限
And it returns an edge detected image which I'm calling edges.
函数会返回出检测好边缘的图像 我将其命名为 edges
Then I'll plot the result.
将结果绘制出来
The Canny algorithm blurs our image automatically,
Canny 算法自动模糊了图像
but you can choose to blur it even more since we're picking up some noise here.
但你可以进一步模糊图像 因为我们发现这里还有一些噪声
But you can see the basic output: Canny
但输出基本就是这样了 Canny
detects the edges of the flower and produces a binary image.
检测出了向日葵的边缘 生成了二值图像
But let's see if we can get even better performance.
不过我们来看能不能有更好的效果
This time, I'll try two different Canny implementations.
这次我要用两种不同的方法来实现 Canny
One, I'll call a wide because it has a very low lower threshold.
一个我称为 wide (宽松) 因为其低阀值很低
And the other I called tight which has a much narrower range for acceptable edges.
第二个我称为 tight (严格) 因为其可接受边缘的范围要相对小得多
And I'll display these two images side by side.
将两张图像并排绘制出来
Here they are. The wide image shows a lot of detected edges,
看到了吧 宽松图能看到很多检测边缘
and the tight shows fewer since the cutoff for weak edges is higher.
而因为弱边缘的筛选阀值较高 所以严格图检测出来的边缘少一些
In both cases, we can see that Canny detects boundaries quite well,
无论是哪一种 我们都可以看到 Canny 很好地检测出了向日葵的轮廓
and produces a binary image within the lines.
而且用细线生成了二值图像
We can especially see that in this tight version.
这点在严格图里更为明显
This becomes very useful when we want to select
如果我们想选出特定区域来进行掩膜操作或进一步分析
a certain area of interest to mask or further analyze.
这一方法十分实用